# **Zijing Shi**

Australian Artificial Intelligence Institute (AAII) Faculty of Engineering and IT (FEIT)

University of Technology Sydney 15 Broadway Ultimo NSW 2007 Australia Phone: +61 0493412836

Email: zijing.shi@student.uts.edu.au Home: https://winni18.github.io/

Research interests

My research interests encompass natural language processing (NLP), reinforcement learning (RL), and machine ethics. Currently, I am focused on the training and application of large language models (LLMs) to enhance their interactive decision-making capabilities, emphasizing trustworthiness,

and ethical considerations.

Education

**University of Technology Sydney** 

Sydney, Australia Mar. 2022 - Present Ph.D. in Computer Science

Mentors: Prof. Ling Chen, Dr. Zuo Hua

Shanghai University

Shanghai, China M.Sc. in Management Science and Engineering Sept. 2018 - June 2021

Mentor: Dr. Nan Jing

Thesis: A Deep Reinforcement Learning-based Investment Portfolio Optimization Strategy

**Shanghai Maritime University** 

Shanghai, China

B.Sc. in Management Science and Engineering

Sept. 2014 - June 2018

Final Year Project: Leveraging Financial Media Sentiment for Stock Price Forecasting through

Naive Bayes and Deep Learning

**Publications** (conference) **Human-Guided Moral Decision Making in Text-based Games** 

Zijing Shi, Meng Fang, Ling Chen, Yali Du, Jun Wang.

The 38-th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2023.

(Special Track on Safe, Robust and Responsible AI)

#### Large Language Models are Neurosymbolic Reasoners

Shilong Deng, Meng Fang, Yudi Zhang, Zijing Shi, Ling Chen, Mykola Pechenizkiy, Jun Wang. The 38-th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2023.

#### CHBias: Bias Evaluation and Mitigation of Chinese Conversational Language Models

Jiaxu Zhao, Meng Fang, **Zijing Shi**, Yitong Li, Ling Chen, Mykola Pechenizkiy.

The 61st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2023.

https://arxiv.org/pdf/2305.11262.pdf

## Stay Moral and Explore: Learn to Behave Morally in Text-based Games

Zijing Shi, Meng Fang, Yunqiu Xu, Ling Chen, Yali Du.

The 11th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.

https://openreview.net/forum?id=CtS2Rs\_aYk

#### **Self-imitation Learning for Action Generation in Text-based Games**

Zijing Shi, Yunqiu Xu, Meng Fang, Ling Chen.

The 17th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL),

https://aclanthology.org/2023.eacl-main.50/

Publications (journal)

Cross-sectional Analysis and Data-driven Forecasting of Confirmed COVID-19 Cases

Nan Jing, **Zijing Shi**, Yi Hu, Ji Yuan

Applied Intelligence, 2022.

https://doi.org/10.1007/s10489-021-02616-8

Forecasting High-frequency Price of Shanghai Copper Futures based on Attention Mechanism and CNN-LSTM (In Chinese)

Nan Jing, Zijing Shi, Yumin Shu

Chinese Journal of Management Science, 2020.

https://doi.org/10.16381/j.cnki.issn1003-207x.2020.0342

Publications (under review)

Large Language Model can be a Moral Compass through Reflection

Zijing Shi, Meng Fang, Ling Chen.

(Under Review, Anonymous Conference)

More than Minorities and Majorities: Understanding Multilateral Bias in Language Generation

Jiaxu Zhao, Yitong Li, **Zijing Shi**, Yulong Pei, Ling Chen, Mykola Pechenizkiy, Meng Fang. (Under Review, Anonymous Conference)

#### Augmenting Neurosymbolic Reasoners via ChatGPT for Text-Based Games

Yudi Zhang, Meng Fang, Zijing Shi, Mykola Pechenizkiy.

(Under Review, Anonymous Conference)

Industry experience

#### **Peng Cheng Laboratory (PCL)**

Shenzhen, China

Research Intern at the Department of Intelligent Computing

Sept. 2021 - Mar. 2022

- Extracted salient factor features from the cryptocurrency market, leveraging analytical techniques to distill meaningful insights.
- Innovatively developed quantitative trading strategies based on deep reinforcement learning, deployed them for real-world testing and performance evaluation.

#### Veighna Technology Co.

Shanghai, China

Quantitative Development and Analysis Intern

Jan. 2021 - May. 2021

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to operate, upgrade and enhance the Veighna, a highly regarded open-source quantitative trading system framework boasting 21,000+ stars on GitHub.
- Created an array of innovative quantitative trading strategies utilizing Veighna.

Research experience

#### **Optimizing Vehicle Scheduling for Electric Logistics Distribution**

Mentor: Prof. Lifeng Mu (Shanghai University)

Dec. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Researched effects of various constraints (capacity, time window, fleet diversity, multi-trip, charging stations) on electric vehicle transport efficiency.
- Developed an advanced algorithm for optimizing EV transport routes, validated using JD.com's logistics data.

Summary of findings available here.

#### **AI-Enhanced Marketing Strategies for Transportation Hubs**

Mentor: Prof. Nan Jing (Shanghai University)

Apr. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- Utilized advanced text analysis to categorize consumer attributes and behaviors.
- $\bullet$  Devised intricate advertising strategies with cutting-edge recommendation algorithms for diverse consumer groups.

# Secured funding via the Shanghai Soft Science Research Project initiative

scholarships First place in UTS School of Computer Science Research Showcase 20 Distinguished Graduate of Shanghai University, Top 5% 20 China National Scholarship for Postgraduate Studies, Top 1% 20
China National Scholarship for Postgraduate Studies, Top 1% 20
1 0
First-Class Postgraduate Scholarship at Shanghai University 20
National Second-Place Award in the 17th Annual China Postgraduate Mathematical Modeling Co
test 20
Runner-Up in China Institute of Innovation's Quantitative Investment Strategy Competition 20
Second-Class Postgraduate Scholarship at Shanghai University 20
National Third-Place Award in the 16th Annual China Postgraduate Mathematical Modeling Co
test 20
First-Class Postgraduate Scholarship at Shanghai University 20
Distinguished Graduate of Shanghai Maritime University, Top 5% 20
Best Final Year Project of of Shanghai Maritime University 20
First-Class Undergraduate Scholarship at Shanghai Maritime University, Top 1% 20

# Skills **Programming**

Proficient in Python, SQL, MATLAB, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Gym, Huggingface, NLTK, spaCy, and more.

### Languages

Mandarin, English